NO BOY NO CRY ore zenshin GO
no boy, no cry, I advance go!
shounen yo kiite kure
hey boys, listen up
ningen nante taishita mon ja nai sa
humans aren't such a big deal
ashita nante moui ranai kara
who needs tomorrow anyway
nigitta kobushi wo kakusu na yo
so don't hide your fists
fuan ni yume wo
you're not old enough
uri tobasu hodo mada oiborechainai daro
to sell your dreams away to uncertainty
shounen yo kokoro no jyuu no
hey boys, you're the only ones
hikigane wo hikeru no wa kimi dake sa
who can pull the trigger in your heart
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
doushi yo mo naku kudaranai
we're living in this senseless, ridiculous,
kono subarashii sekai ni tattaima ikiteiru kara
awesome world right at this moment,
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
subete no hontou to uso wo
don't forget every truth or lie
kesshite wasurete shima wa nai you ni
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
shinu ni wa mosugiru darou
we're way too young to die
shiraketa tsura ga naranderu karappo no kono machi de
in this empty town lined with empty faces
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids took off
kaze no nai kono yoru ni
into this windless night
nanika wo kaeyou to shiteru kara
because they want to change something
A Funeral March
For the Living
Wh-Why...
Why does such
a good man have to... die?!
It's sad...
It's so sad!
I remember now...
I forgot when,
but you showed it to me, didn't you?
With a twinkle in your eye,
you proudly said it was
a memento of your father.
That was the pipe box, wasn't it?
It was an amazing box.
No wonder you're so proud of it...
Even though I took it and smashed it,
you only laughed.
You were smiling when
we kicked you and tossed you.
It was a great smile.
Really...
Hold it in, Rokusuke!
They'll all be gone.
If we let this moment go,
there will be no other chance
to get out of the village.
But Kanpachi is...!
It's for the village,
we have to do something and
make our way to that village!
Yeah...
Funerals are awesome, aren't they!
I wanna do that again.
One... two... three people...
got away again...
Looks like we can have
another funeral.
This is...
The Village Hidden in the Leaves.
You are...?
Uzumaki Naruto! Right now,
I'm in the middle of training.
The Village Hidden in the Leaves...
H-Hey! I said hey!
Hang in there!
This is training too...!
I can't give up yet! Not yet!
The escort for the ruler of
the Land of Swamps, Lord Chichiyasu,
was completed without incident!
Well done.
That's Tsunade-sama's...!
Excellent dumplings are always
from the Leaf Village, aren't they?
That was my last one!
Mission Accomplished!
I came to pound the pirates
of the Gottani Channel
with the fist of love!
If they take this opportunity
to rehabilitate themselves,
it's worth while to shed a tear!
I'll have your team do it for me.
Yes?
Even though we're already busy,
that Naruto brought in more work.
After this, Guy has the S-rank mission.
The client picked him,
so he must depart today.
So, do it without Guy.
That's pretty straightforward...
I called Hyuga Neji,
Tenten and Lee.
Ohh!
My pupils can undertake the fulfillment
of this mission without incident!
Wait...
Take Uzumaki Naruto, too.
Why can't it just be my pupils,
who are loved by all the world?
Please answer me, Tsunade-sama!
It just is.
Hidden Leaf Hospital
Those three people that Naruto saved
came all the way
from the Katabami Gold Mine
to request a mission.
Katabami Gold Mine is one of
the Land of Rivers' greatest mines,
but about half a year ago, hooligans
calling themselves the Kurosuki family
appeared on the pretext of guarding it,
and took control of the village...
killing villagers for
no particular reason.
How vile!
Your mission is this:
Once those three have
regained their strength,
escort them to Katabami Gold Mine
and eliminate the Kurosuki family.
It's a simple mission.
Well anyway, it must be a group
of punks who're after money.
Why did you call me for
such an easy mission?
Who do you think you are?
I'm busy searching for
Sasuke and training, and...!
You forced your way into missions
that you weren't called for.
It's not a Genin's place
to choose his missions!
Would you like to be sent back
to the Academy? Well?!
— Hyuga Neji!
— Yes!
You're the leader!
It will be good training for you
to try to tame the unstable.
I don't want to...
but, I'll do it!
I'll go continue my training!
Hey, Naruto!
Please excuse them.
They have no manners...
Wait!
Those little brats...!
What the hell do
they think missions are?!
Umm, excuse me?
What?!
The Kurosuki Family...
What did you say
their boss' name was?
Raiga!
That's what I thought...
What?
Well, on a previous mission,
I heard a rumor about him.
A rumor...?
Pervy Sage hasn't returned...
I'm forced to go on a mission...
Oh, this is irritating...
Sakura!
Naruto?
What's going on? A bird?
Yesterday I found it injured
and treated it, but...
Sakura, that's amazing!
But poor thing.
It's separated from its friends.
Naruto!
Oh, sorry, did I intrude?
You intruded big time!
No, no!
Don't turn your back,
no need to grovel to youth.
Sakura, Hello!
Hello!
What did you come here for?
— Just to have a word.
— Huh? What the...?!
Oh, Sakura, goodbye!
— Hey! What was that?!
— She went wild, didn't she?
She should act her age.
What?! The boss of
the Kurosuki family
is one of the Seven Ninja
Swordsmen of the Mist?
Yeah, it's exclusive information
from our respected teacher, Guy.
Who're the Seven Ninja
Swordsmen of the Mist?
Naruto, you said that
you fought in the Land of
the Waves mission, didn't you?
At that time...
Oh, Zabuza! And?
And Guy-sensei and Kakashi-sensei
fought Kisame Hoshigaki.
I heard that
you met them there too, Naruto.
Oh! I know that guy!
Those two were once called
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen
of the Mist.
And at that time,
who was with Kisame Hoshigaki?
Oh!
The man called Itachi!
And then?
You still don't understand?
If Raiga is one of the Seven Ninja
Swordsmen of the Mist,
then he's probably tied to Itachi
who was with Kisame.
Oh! And?
Tell me, who's after Itachi?
I know! Sasuke!
That's right!
We can probably get
the clue to Sasuke's whereabouts
at Katabami Gold Mine!
But...
If that's what Guy-sensei said then...
Don't say anything rude!
It's information that's
100% reliable!
Starting now,
while guarding Rokusuke and the others,
we head toward Katabami Gold Mine
to fulfill our mission to
wipe out the Kurosuki family.
There's a shop I'm familiar
with close to the gold mine.
Let's make that the base.
What do you mean
a shop you're familiar with?
That's the fun part of the trip.
That aside, that Naruto is late...
If the source of the information
is Guy-sensei,
maybe he couldn't quite trust it?
That's not true!
Naruto will definitely come!
That's because Guy-sensei's
information is correct!
Whatever.
Here I am!
We're all here so...!
Is that for you to say?!
Let's go!
So... which way?
Don't be so anxious, Rokusuke,
Those guys will save our town.
It's post-meal training!
I won't lose!
How long do you intend
to rest here?!
If we hurry, we can save Kanpachi
from the burial...
Give it up...
How long do you think
it's been since that happened?
It's painful but...
I remember... this sleepiness.
The shop is close by.
You say you're sleepy,
and are you walking in your sleep?!
It's okay.
I slept while on a marathon on
this road for three days straight.
You are joking, right?
It's true.
The track meet of my youth
with Guy-sensei.
My body still remembers it.
I've gotten sleepy.
Hey, Bushy Brow,
are you really okay?
That's right. In this area,
there's the scent of spicy curry.
Curry? Now that you mention it...
That's right!
Over there, it's...
the Curry of Life Shop!
Grandma Sansho!
Oh my...
Oh goodness!
I haven't seen you for a while!
— Oh my my my!
— You're looking well!
This is the shop Lee is familiar with?
That mountain is
the Katabami Gold Mine
Grandma Sansho's curry saved my life.
So you're saying
it's delicious curry?
No, it really saved my life.
I'm indebted to this curry.
It was when
I'd just become a Genin...
When Guy-sensei gave me
a special training routine.
Oh my, that's right.
I remember.
Do your best!
Oh my...
Hey, Grandma Sansho!
Oh my, they've come again!
Those people are running in their sleep.
Karashi! Karashi!
If you had that kind of energy,
you wouldn't lose to the bullies.
Oh my,
I might have said too much.
Curry of Life Shop
Oh my! It's the third day.
They've been running the whole time.
Oh my. What a problem.
I wonder if he's hungry...?
What a pickle! He's not waking up!
Maybe I didn't use
enough spice?
Karashi...
I've never seen a person
who works this hard.
Oh really... so you want to help
this young man too...?
This is the curry of life.
Now! Grandma Sansho went to
the trouble of making this curry.
Let's eat!
I'm digging in!
Yum!
This is yummy-yum delicious!
Delicious! The use of spices
is wonderful!
And this rice
goes perfectly with the curry!
Delicious!
By the way, I don't see Karashi.
Karashi saw how hard you worked
and became a bright kid
full of energy, but...
He got too much energy
and left for town.
What?
I was wrong to keep telling him
to be stronger.
"I'm going to be a man!"
"I'm going to be part of
the Kurosuki family," he said.
Oh my! I'm not blaming you.
Don't worry.
It's too late.
I'm responsible...
Oh my.
Neji!
Please include Karashi's rescue
into our mission!
We'll bring him back from
the road of evil!
It's fine.
We'll use this shop as a base
and take a good look into the village.
Then we'll come up with a strategy
and spring into action.
Yes!
You guys await orders here.
Because it's dangerous
if the Kurosuki family finds us.
It's a disaster!
Rokusuke! Rokusuke!
He's gone!
I'm sure he went to town alone!
That's not good!
If those guys find Rokusuke...!
Now that it's come to this,
we don't have time
to come up with a strategy!
Let's get right to it!
No!
We'll get right to it!
Let's hurry.
Wait for me, Kanpachi,
I'm coming now...
Someone... is coming...
Aw, again...
I have to put on a funeral!
kusottare na nyuusu ga toori sugite
crappy news pass us by
kimi wa kotoba wo nakusu
and you become speechless
boku no koe ja marude chiisa sugite
my voice is way too soft
kimi wa henji mo shinai
so you don't answer
kimi ga naiteru hitori de naiteru
you're crying, crying alone
boku wa dou suru boku mo naiteru no sa
what can I do? I'm crying too
yoru ni hitoribocchi no ore no sakebi ni nosete
"let my lonely scream ring out through the night"
zawameku jidai wo ore no supiido de buttobashiteku yeah yeah yeah yeah
I'll thrash this confused era with my speed, yeah
sanzameku yoru mo ore no supiido de buttobashiteku yeah yeah yeah yeah
and I'll thrash this confused night with my speed, yeah
tsunzaku gitaa to ore no supiido de buttobashiteku yeah yeah yeah yeah
I'll thrash them with my piercing guitar and my speed, yeah
katamuku sekai mo warui yatsura mo kechirashiteku yeah yeah yeah yeah
I'll take this sinking world, all its evil bastards, and kick their butts, yeah
You taught me that day.
If you cook with great care,
you can save someone's life
with just one serving of curry.
Even for a person like me,
with intense effort,
it's not an impossibility...
That's what I thought.
You were far more admirable
back then, Karashi.
But...
Next time:
"Reach the Soul! Fist of Love."